Worst. Renaissance. Fair. Ever.
史上  最烂 文艺 复兴节 集会
Renaissance Fair
美国很多地方举办的
重现文艺复兴时期场景的庆典活动
Please let it go, Sheldon.
别再说了 Sheldon
It was rife with historical inaccuracies.
到处充斥着历史错误
For example, the tavern girl serving flagons of mead.
比如 小酒馆的女服务生
售卖大肚壶的蜂蜜酒
Her costume was obviously Germanic.
她的装束明显是德国人
But in 1487, the Bavarian purity laws, or "Reinheitsgebot,"
但在1487年 纯净酿酒法
或曰"德国啤酒纯正法"
severely limited the
availability of mead.
严格限制加制蜂蜜酒
*****
该法明定啤酒的酿造原料 尤其不得添加人工酒精
At best, they would have
had some sort of spiced wine.
最多只准加点葡萄酒
You're nitpicking.
你是鸡蛋里挑骨头
Oh, really?
哦 是么?
Well, here's another nit for you: the flagons
would not have been made of polypropylene.
再告诉你个错误
大肚酒壶不该是聚丙烯做的
Renaissance fairs aren't about historical accuracy.
文艺复兴节关注的不是历史错误
They're about taking chubby girls who work at Kinko's
而是让那些在金考公司上班的圆胖女孩
and lacing them up in corsets so tight
their bosom jumps out and says, "Howdy."
用带子把腹部束得紧紧的以致
乳房鼓得快跳脱出来 然后说"您好"
Bosoms would not have said
"howdy" in the 15th century.
15世纪的大胸女人可不会说"您好"
If anything, they
would've said, "Huzzah."
说的话也该是 "啊赞!"
I don't care what the
bosoms say, Sheldon.
我不在乎大胸女人说什么 Sheldon
I just want to be part
of the conversation.
我只想和她们搭上话
Hi, guys.
嗨 伙计们
Looks like you've been
to the renaissance fair...
看来你们去参加了文艺复兴节集会
I'm hoping.
我希望是
Renaissance fair?
文艺复兴节?
More of a medieval, slash, Age of Enlightenment,
slash, any-excuse- to-wear-a-codpiece fair.
不过是个中世纪的/启蒙时代的/
找借口穿下体盖的节日
...........
15、16世纪男子短裤前面所悬的袋状物
Okay, fine, whatever.
好吧 随意啦
You guys, this is my friend Eric.
伙计们 这是我朋友Eric
Hello.
你好
So, yeah, good to see you.
嗯 很高兴见到你
Yeah. Yeah. It's good to see you, too.
是啊 我也很高兴见到你
We should probably go. Bye, guys.
我们该走了 拜 伙计们
I like your hat.
我喜欢你的帽子
Thanks, my mom made it.
谢了 我妈做的
Penny with a new guy, tres awkward.
Penny带了个新家伙 三倍尴尬
It wasn't awkward.
并不尴尬啊
It wasn't fun.
也没啥意思
Besides, what's the big deal?
再说 有啥大不了滴?
We dated, we stopped dating,
and now we're both moving on.
我们约会过 然后不约会了
现在我们都朝前看了
KOOTHRAPPALI: By moving on, do you
mean she's going out with other men
你指的朝前看是她和另个男的出去约会
and you spent the afternoon making
15th-century soap with Wolowitz?
而你花一下午和Wolowitz一起
做15世纪的肥皂?
That was not 15th century soap.
那才不是15世纪的肥皂
My God, those people need to
learn you can't just put "ye olde"
天啊 这些人该懂得不能什么
都胡乱加上前缀"ye olde"（古英语：老）
in front of anything you want
and expect to get away with it.
就指望侥幸蒙混过关
Can we please just go in?
我们能快点进去吗?
My chain mail's stuck in my underwear.
我的锁子甲和我内裤粘一起了
You're wearing modern underwear?
你穿着现代人的内裤?
Relatively modern.
相对比较现代
Why, what are you wearing?
怎么了 你穿的什么?
I fashioned historically accurate
undergarments out of linen.
我精确地遵照历史
穿的是亚麻内衣哟
You went out and bought linen?
你还出去买了亚麻布?
Don't be silly-- I borrowed
one of your pillowcases.
别傻了 我从你的枕套里借了一块
Borrowed?
借?
-=伊甸园美剧http://sfile.ydy.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=伊甸园美剧http://sfile.ydy.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: 奕鹂ＢＩＲＤ 饭特稀
校对: irenenadal
时间轴: 咔肉肉
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: 奕鹂ＢＩＲＤ 饭特稀
校对: irenenadal
时间轴: 咔肉肉
双语:徐小帆
天才理论传
第二季 第2集
***It gives me the
freedom to move on myself.
我很高兴看到Penny释怀了
这给了我自己朝前看的自由
Are you saying that
you've been holding back?
你是说你之前在原地踌躇?
Of course. Out of respect.
当然 出于尊重嘛
So, how do you explain
the ten years before Penny?
那你怎么解释遇见Penny前的十年?
Who were you respecting then?
那时你是为了尊重谁?
Well, I've dated plenty of women.
我和许多女生交往过
There was Joyce Kim... Leslie Winkle...
Joyce Kim还有Leslie Winkle...
Notify the editors of the Oxford English Dictionary.
通知牛津英语词典的编辑们
The word "plenty" has been
redefined to mean "two."
"许多"现在被重新定义为"两个"
What about that girl
last year at Comic-Con?
那去年Comic-con动漫展上的女生呢?
Doesn't count.
不算
Why not?
为什么?
What happens in costume at
Comic-Con stays at Comic-Con.
穿着戏服在动漫展上发生的故事
只限于动漫展
You're only saying that
because of what happened to you.
你这么说只因为发生在你身上的事
What happened to you?
你发生了什么事?
Nothing happened to me.
我没什么事
It wasn't your fault, Raj.
不是你的错 Raj
He was dressed as a
green Orion slave girl.
他把自己打扮成俄里翁的年轻女仆
.......
希腊神话中的猎人 为阿忒拉斯的七个女儿所爱
How did we get on me?
怎么说到我头上了?
We were mocking Leonard
for not moving on.
我们在嘲笑Leonard原地踌躇
Dude, you have totally not moved on.
老兄 你完全是在原地徘徊
Yes, I have.
是这样
It's just a matter of actually
making a date with someone.
不过就是个和谁定个具体约会的问题呗
Like who?
比如和谁?
Well... there's Joyce Kim.
呃...不有Joyce Kim嘛
But she defected back to North Korea, so
that's a little geographically undesirable.
但她叛逃回朝鲜了
所以有点地域上的不适宜捏
What about Leslie Winkle?
那Leslie Winkle呢?
Oh, no.
哦 不
Why?
怎么了?
Her research methodology is sloppy, she's
unjustifiably arrogant about loop quantum gravity,
她的研究方法很马虎
在圈量子引力上又盲目自大
and to make matters worse,
she's often mean to me.
更糟的是 她对我刻薄得要命
I think she's smoking hot.
我觉得她辣得冒烟啊
I'd hit that.
同意
（也有"我也有性趣"之意)
You'd hit particulate soil in a colloidal suspension.
你应该用胶状悬浮体击打土颗粒
（调侃"hit"的原意)
Mud.
就是泥呗
Look, I like Leslie, but she's not interested in
dating as much as using men as tools for stress release.
我喜欢Leslie 但她对约会没兴趣
不过是把男人作释放压力的工具
Yeah, so? Be a tool.
是吗 那又怎样?就作工具呗
Go get yourself a little
rebound "stress release."
你自己去感受下反弹回的"释放的压力"呗
（rebound也有分手后后备女友之意)
Technically, it would only be rebound if he and
Penny had actually engaged in physical intimacy.
严格讲 他只有和Penny
有身体亲密行为才能有后备女友一说
You mean like you and
Richard the slave girl?
你是说你和Richard那个女仆那样的?
I bought him dinner and we kissed once!
我给他买了晚餐然后接吻一次
That was it.
仅此而已
And he told me his name was Kimberly.
然后他告诉我他叫Kimberly
You know how I know
we're not in the matrix?
知道我如何认识到
我们不身在黑客帝国（matrix原意:子宫)吗?
How?
如何?
If we were, the food would be better.
如果那样 食物会好很多
Hey, Leonard.
嘿 Leonard
- Hey, Leslie.
- Hey, dummy.
- 嘿 Leslie
- 嘿 小傻瓜
Hello, to you...
嗨 是你啊...
insufficiently intelligent person.
智力水平不够高的人
Ooh, rush me to the burn unit.
哇 赶紧送我去烧伤科
Hey, Leonard, do you have a
second? I need to ask you something.
嘿 Leonard 你有空吗?我要问你些事
Sure.
当然
Well, if you'll excuse me, I'm going to go
do work that promises significant results,
失陪了哦 我要去工作了
将来会有重大成果
as opposed to what you do...
与你的工作恰恰相反
which does not.
毫无成果
Yeah, you heard me.
没错 你听见了吧
So, I heard your relationship
with Penny crashed to the ground
我听说你和Penny的交往关系分崩离析
like blue ice falling out
of an airplane lavatory.
就像从飞机马桶里蹦出的蓝冰一样
Where did you hear that?
你从哪儿听说的?
Actually, I read it. Wolowitz texted me.
实际上 我读到的 Wolowitz发短信给我
Like blue ice falling out of
an airplane lavatory, yeah.
就像从飞机马桶里蹦出的蓝冰 是啊
I thought it was a pretty
good one. I gave him an LOL.
我觉得是条不错的短信 所以回复他^_^
Anyway, it got me thinking.
总之 我就在想
Now that you're unattached, maybe we
can revisit our previous attachment.
既然你又单身了
也许我们能重温过去的情结
Are you suggesting another
bout of stress release?
你是建议再来一次释放压力的较量?
No, I'm all done with casual sex.
不 我已经厌烦"逢场作性"了
From now on, I'm fully committed to
the traditional relationship paradigm.
从现在起
我完全忠于传统交往关系的模式
Really? What changed?
真的吗? 哪变了呀?
It's hard to say.
很难说
I guess there's just a
time in every woman's life
我猜每个女人的一生中都会有段时间
when she gets tired of waking up on a strange
futon with a bunch of people she doesn't know.
厌倦了在陌生的床垫上醒来
发现身边一群不认识的人
Yeah, I can see how that
would-- a bunch of people?
嗯 我能理解 怎么是一群人?
Anyway, I figure it's
time to slow things down
总之 我想是时候要慢下脚步
and who better to slow
things down with than you?
而谁比你更慢脚步呢?
I'm flattered.
承蒙夸奖
So how do you suggest we proceed?
那你建议我们怎么进行呢?
Your place, we'll order Chinese,
you'll rent a movie-- artsy,
你家 我们点些中国菜
租部电影 艺术点的
but accessible-- then
light petting, no coitus.
但要易理解 然后轻柔抚摸 没有性交
Sounds fun.
听起来很有趣
I'll leave the details up to you.
细节由你来定
I think it's better if you assume the male role.
我想如果你扮演男性角色 这样好些
Thank you, that's very thoughtful.
谢谢你 很体贴
Great. Call me.
好极了 打电话给我哟
Great news.
好消息
My mom sent me my old Nintendo 64.
我妈给我寄来我原来的任天堂64
........
家用游戏主机任天堂64
最后一款使用游戏卡的游戏主机
Terrific.
好耶
You know what this means, don't you?
你知道这意味着什么吧?
Break out the Red Bull, it's
time to rock Mario, old school.
爆发红牛舞
到了玩超级玛丽的时候咯 重温旧梦啊
I kind of have other plans tonight.
我今晚另有安排耶
But it's Friday.
但今天是周五
Friday's always vintage game night.
周五总是古董游戏之夜啊
Look, Mom included the memory card.
瞧 妈妈还寄了存储卡
We can pick up right where I left off
in 1999 when I had pernicious anemia.
我们可以刚好从1999年我得恶性贫血
暂停那会儿开始玩
Well, the thing is,
someone's coming over.
问题是 有人要过来
Okay, no problem. I have three
controllers. The more the merrier.
好的 没问题
我有三个手柄 人越多越开心
Sheldon, it's a date. I
have a date coming over.
Sheldon 是约会 我的约会对象要过来
Well, you can't blame me for
not jumping to that conclusion.
你可不能怪我没早点反映过来哦
Why? What's so unusual
about me having a date?
为什么? 我有约会就这么不寻常?
- Well, statistically speaking...
- All right, all right.
- 从统计学上讲...
- 好了好了
Well, nevertheless, I have one now and I'd appreciate
it if you would, you know, make yourself scarce.
不过我现在有对象了
如果你能回避 我不胜感激（scarce原意稀有)
Leonard, I'm a published theoretical
physicist with two doctorates
Leonard 我是拥有2个博士头衔
发表过理论的物理学家
and an IQ which can't be
accurely measured by normal tests.
并且智商高到无法用普通测试测出
How much scarcer could I be?
我还不够稀有吗?
You know what I mean.
你明白我的意思
Could you just give us a little privacy?
你不能给我们一点私人空间吗?
You want me to leave the apartment?
你要我离开公寓?
Yes.
是的
You mean, just go
someplace else and be...
你是说 去别的地方...
someplace else?
别的地方?
Yes.
是的
Well, why should I leave?
This is my apartment, too.
为什么我要离开?这也是我的公寓
I know it is, and if science ever
discovers a second member of your species
我知道 如果科学领域
发现第二个像你这样的人类
and you two would like some privacy, I'd
be more than happy to get out of your way.
你俩想要独处 我很乐意为你们回避
Well, all right then.
那好吧
Sheldon, what are you doing?
Sheldon 你在干嘛?
Playing Super Mario on a poorly
coded Nintendo 64 emulator.
在编码不佳的任天堂64模拟器上
玩超级玛丽
Yeah, but why are you
doing it on the stairs?
但你干嘛坐楼梯上玩?
I am a modern day Napoleon exiled
to the Elba of the staircase
我是现代版的拿破仑
被放逐到楼梯版的厄尔巴岛
because Leonard, get this, has a date.
因为Leonard 注意 在约会
Oh, well, good for him.
好 不错嘛他
Yeah, but why are you sitting here?
嗯 但你为什么坐这儿?
Why don't you just go
to a movie or something?
干嘛不去看电影啥的?
Alone?
一个人?
Yeah, why not?
是啊 为什么不?
What if I choke on my popcorn?
要是我被爆米花噎住了呢?
Who will administer
the Heimlich maneuver?
谁来做海姆利克氏操作法?
Well, then don't order popcorn.
那就别买爆米花呗
No popcorn at the mov...
listen to yourself.
看电影不买爆米花... 你自己听听
Why don't you go to a cfee shop?
那去咖啡店如何?
I don't drink coffee.
我不喝咖啡
They have other things.
他们还有别的东西
What do they have?
什么?
I don't know. You know,
cookies, pastries...
不清楚 大概有饼干 油酥面团...
Pastries such as bear claws?
熊爪糕之类的?
(一种杏仁味早餐糕点 形似熊爪)
- Yeah, sure.
- I don't like bear claws.
- 没错
- 我不喜欢吃熊爪糕
Hey, Penny. Dumbass.
嘿 Penny 傻蛋
Leslie Winkle.
Leslie Winkle
Of all the overrated physicists
in all the labs in all the world,
这世上有这么多被高估的物理学家
why does it have to be Leslie Winkle?
为什么非得是Leslie Winkle?
Well, they have a lot in common.
嗯... 他们有许多共同之处
I mean, they're both scientists.
我是说 他们都是科学家
Oh, please.
噢 得了吧
The only way she could make a contribution to science
would be if they resumed sending chimps into space.
要是他们重新启动送猩猩上天的计划
她倒是还有可能为科学作出点贡献
Okay, well, I have a
date, too, so I'll see ya.
好吧 我也有约会 回见啦
Everybody has a date.
大家都有约会
Even you, Mario, going
after Princess Peach.
连你玛丽都在追求桃子公主
And what am I doing?
I'm just enabling you.
而我在做啥? 不过是操纵你追她罢了
This is pretty good orange chicken.
这陈皮鸡味道真不赖
Yeah, it's from Chang's.
没错 去陈记买的嘛
- Not Chow's?
- No, Chang's.
- 不是周记?
- 不 是陈记
- What happened to Chow's?
- It changed.
- 周记是怎么了?
- 它变了
So, how many children do
you think we should have?
那么 我们该生几个小孩?
I'm sorry.
抱歉
That was a little abrupt.
有点唐突了
A little?
只是有点?
I mean, there are so many things to talk
about before we discuss reproduction.
我是说 在我们讨论繁衍后代之前
还有好多事要谈呢
I sure hope so.
当然 我希望如此
Besides shortness, what genetic
weaknesses run in your family?
除了矮小 你家还有啥基因缺陷?
Sorry to interrupt.
Battery's dying. Continue.
抱歉打扰了 没电了 你们继续
Uh, genetic weakness, right.
呃... 基因缺陷 有了
Uh, there's the lactose intolerance.
我有乳糖不耐症
Don't forget the male-pattern baldness.
别忘了还有男性型秃发
When his uncles sit around the dinner
table, they look like a half carton of eggs.
他的叔叔们围坐餐桌前的情形
就像是看到了半箱鸡蛋一样
Okay, yeah, my uncles are bald,
好吧 我的叔叔都是秃头
but my Aunt Edna is one of the
hairiest women you'll ever meet, so...
不过我阿姨Edna将是你见过的头发最茂盛的
Sweet lady.
挺和蔼可亲的
Always tickles when she hugs me.
抱我的时候老是会痒痒
What now?
又怎么了?
I have to make pee-pee.
我要尿尿
Listen, I'm sorry about all
of Sheldon's interruptions.
听着 Shelon老是来打扰 我为此抱歉
He can be a bit of an eccentric.
他的举止是有点古怪
If by "eccentric" you mean passive-aggressive
East Texas blowhole, I agree.
要是你说的"举止古怪"是指他表面看起来支持我们
实际却老在背地里捣乱 我很同意
I think tonight was a very good start.
我觉得今晚是个很不错的开端
Me, too.
我也是
Are you sure you're okay postponing intercourse until
our relationship is past the initial viability test?
在我们的关系通过"生存能力大考验"之前
你确定不和我发生关系?
No, problem. I'm very skilled
at postponing intercourse.
没问题 我对延迟交配很在行
I guess I'll call you and
we'll arrange another evening.
我会再打给你的 哪天晚上再过来
Yes, I believe protocol dictates
that you wait a minimum of 18 hours
没错 我们不是有约定咩
你至少得在18个小时之后才打给我
before you call so I'm not
repulsed by your cloying eagerness.
不然我会对你如此猴急反感的
Sure.
当然
Again, it's your
decision. You're the man.
再说一遍 这是你决定的 你是男人
PENNY: It wasn't my cat.
那不是我的猫
It was an experiment designed
by this guy named Schroedinger.
是一个叫薛定谔的家伙设计的实验
（上季也有提及:薛定谔的猫）
ERIC: From the Charlie Brown cartoons?
查理布朗动画里的人物?
PENNY: No, he was some kind of
scientist. Let me start again.
不 他是个啥科学家的 我们从头来过
- Oh, hey, Leonard.
- Hello.
- 嘿 Leonard
- 好啊
Leslie.
Leslie
Okay, well, good night.
好吧 晚安啦
That ain't gonna make your point.
这样子可不够
That's enough.
够了够了
Call me.
打给我哦
Right.
好
- Okay, good night.
- Uh, what?
- 晚安
- 什么?
Had a great time. Ciao.
今晚很高兴 再见
I'm sorry, I am not going
back to the renaissance fair.
对不起 我可不想再去什么文艺复兴节了
Come on, Sheldon.
得了吧 Sheldon
There's so few places I
can wear my jester costume.
我还能穿小丑服去啥别的地方咩
I don't care.
我不管
There are far too many historical
anomalies for my comfort.
这么多奇怪的人和物 打着历史的名号
Okay, how about this?
你看这样如何?
You can go dressed as a Star Trek science officer
exploring a planet similar to Earth in the 1500s.
你可以打扮成星际迷航里的科学家
在十五世纪探索一个和地球类似的行星
You mean, like Spock?
你是说像"尖耳朵"史波克那样?
Sure.
没错
Fascinating.
太棒了
Hey, fellow scientists...
嘿 我的科学家同事们
Sheldon.
Sheldon
Why don't we all move over
there so Leslie can join us?
我们不如坐那儿吧 这样Leslie就能一起了
Yeah, let's do it.
好 我们过去吧
If you're having trouble deciding where to
sit, may I suggest one potato, two potato?
如果你不知道该坐哪儿 我建议你念
"一个土豆 两个土豆"(一种美国小孩玩的顺口溜)
Or as I call it, the Leslie
Winkle experimental methodology.
或者按我的叫法 Leslie Winkle的实验方法论
Don't make this hard for me.
别让我左右为难
It's not hard. It's simple.
这又不难 简单得很
You can either sit with me, your
friend, colleague and roommate
你可以和我坐一起 你的朋友同事兼室友
or you can sit with an overrated
scientist you might have sex with.
或者你可以和那个被高估的科学家坐一起
反正你们马上就会发生性行为了
You're right, it is simple.
你说对了 这很简单
Hey, Sheldon.
嘿 Sheldon
Penny.
Penny
Third floor tonight--
mixing it up?
今晚坐三楼哈 吵架了?
I still don't understand why you
don't just go to dinner or something.
我还是不明白你为啥不去吃个饭之类的
All right, let's say I go to dinner alone, and
during the meal, I have to use the restroom.
好吧 就说我一个人去吃饭吧
在用餐期间 我肯定得去洗手间
How do I know someone's
not touching my food?
我怎么知道别人没碰过我的食物?
Good night, Sheldon.
晚安 Sheldon
Penny, hold on.
Penny 等等
Are you sure things can't
work out with you and Leonard?
你肯定你和Leonard没可能了?
Excuse me?
什么?
I'm just wondering if you really
gave it the old college try.
我只是想知道你会不会努力试试
(这里是个双关语 也指Penny试着去念大学)
Or in your case, the old
community college try.
放在你身上 就是去社区学院试试
Okay, where is this coming from?
干嘛要提起这个?
Leonard is upstairs right
now with my archenemy.
Leonard和我的宿敌在楼上
Your archenemy?
你的宿敌?
Yes, the Dr. Doom to my Mr. Fantastic.
没错 就像毁灭博士对我的神奇先生
Dr. Octopus to my Spider-Man, the
Dr. Sivana to my Captain Marvel.
章鱼博士对我的蜘蛛侠
Sivana博士对我的神奇队长
I get it, I get it, I get it.
明白了 明白了
Do you know, it's amazing how many
supervillains have advanced degrees.
真是奇妙 这些超级大坏蛋都有很高的学历
Graduate school should probably do a
better job of screening those people out.
研究生院该好好做做工作把他们筛选出嘛
Sheldon, come back. You're losing me.
Sheldon 快说正题 你把我弄晕了
It's Leslie Winkle, Penny.
Penny 我说的是Leslie Winkle
She belittles my research.
她鄙视我的研究
Oh, sweetie, I'm sorry.
噢 小可爱 我很抱歉
She called me "dumbass."
她叫我"傻蛋"
I know. I heard.
我知道 我听见了
Given this situation, I have no choice
but to withdraw my previous objections
在这种情况下 我不得不收回之前
to your ill-considered
relationship with Leonard.
对你和Leonard欠考虑关系的反对
Oh, gee, well, thank you for that.
噢 谢谢你这么做
But I think for now, Leonard and
I are just gonna stay friends.
不过就现在而言
Leonard和我还是做朋友比较好
No, that response is unacceptable to me.
不行 这个回答我无法接受
Sheldon, you are a smart guy.
Sheldon 你是个聪明人
- You must know...
- I'm "smart"?
- 你得知道
- 我是"聪明人"?
I'd have to lose 60 IQ points
to be classified as "smart."
要被归为"聪明人" 我得去掉60点智商才行
- Are you gonna let me talk?
- I'm sorry.
- 你还让不让我说了?
- 对不起
You must know that if Leonard and Leslie want to
be together, nothing you can do is gonna stop it.
你得知道要是Leonard和Leslie要在一起的话
你做什么都是阻止不了的
You continue to underestimate
my capabilities, madam.
小姐 你再次低估了我的能力
Okay, let me put it this way.
好 这么说吧
If you're really Leonard's friend, you will
support him no matter who he wants to be with.
如果你真是Leonard的哥们
无论他和谁在一起你都会支持他的
Wait a minute.
等一下
Why am I doing all the giving here?
为什么我要他们让地儿?
If Leonard's really my friend, why doesn't he
have to support me an my hatred of Leslie Winkle?
如果Leonard真的是我的哥们
他怎么就不支持一下我对Leslie Winkle的厌恶之情?
Because love trumps hate.
因为爱胜过厌恶
Oh, now you're just making stuff up.
噢 你可真会胡说
Okay, good night, Sheldon.
好吧 晚安了 Sheldon
Oh, Mario, if only I could control
everyone the way I control you.
玛丽啊
要是我能像控制你一样控制他人该多好
Hop, you little plumber, hop, hop, hop.
跳啊 你个小水管工 跳 跳 跳
When the two of you reach a natural
stopping point, I'd like to have a word.
等你们自然地结束以后 我有话要说
The word is "pee-pee." Just do it.
要是你要说"尿尿" 去就是了
Leonard, you're my friend, and friends
support their friends... apparently.
Leonard 你是我朋友
朋友互相支持 那是显然的
So I'm withdrawing my objection to your
desire to have a relationship with Leslie.
所以我收回对你和Leslie交往的反对
Thank you.
谢谢
I will graciously overlook the fact
that she is an arrogant, subpar scientist
我会和蔼地远眺这位傲慢而不合格的科学家
who actually believes loop quantum
gravity better unites quantum mechanics
实际上她相信环量子引力更好地联系起
量子力学和广义相对论
with generally relativity
than does string theory.
而不是弦理论
You kids have fun.
你们自娱自乐吧
Hang on a second.
等等
Loop quantum gravity clearly offers more
testable predictions than string theory.
环量子引力明显比弦理论提供了更多可证的预测
I'm listening. Amuse me.
我在听呢 逗我笑吧
Okay, well, for one thing, we expect
quantized space-time to manifest itself
好 一方面来说
我们期待量子化的时空能够证明
as minute differences in the speed
of light for different colors.
在光速下不同颜色的细小差异
Balderdash. Matter clearly
consists of tiny strings.
胡言乱语 物质显然是由细小的弦组成的
Are you gonna let him
talk to me like that?
他这么同我说话 你就坐视不理?
Okay, well, there is a lot
of merit to both theories.
好吧 两种理论各有各的优势
No, there isn't.
不是这样的
Only loop quantum gravity calculates
the entropy of black holes.
只有环量子引力能算出黑洞的熵值
Sheldon, don't make that noise.
Sheldon 别发出那种声音
It's disrespectful.
太不尊重人了
I should hope so. It
was a snort of derision.
我正是这么想的 那是嘲笑的鼻息声
You agree with me, right?
你同意我的 对吧?
Loop quantum gravity is
the future of physics.
环量子引力是物理学的未来
Sorry, Leslie, I guess I prefer
my space stringy, not loopy.
抱歉 Leslie
我比较同意弦理论 而不是环理论
I'm glad I found out the truth about
you before this went any further.
我很高兴能在我们的关系有进展前看到了真相
Truth? What truth?
真相? 什么真相?
We're talking about untested
hypotheses. It's no big deal.
我们在讨论未经证实的假说 有什么大不了的
It isn't? Really?
没什么大不了的? 真的?
Tell me, Leonard, how
will we raise the children?
Leonard 告诉我 我们怎么教育我们的孩子
I...
我...
I guess we wait until they're old enough
and let them choose their own theory.
我猜我们会等他们长大了自己选吧
We can't let them choose,
Leonard. They're children!
怎么能让他们自己选 他们是孩子!
Wait. Where are you going?
等等 你上哪儿去?
I'm sorry.
对不起
I could have accepted our
kids being genetically unable
就遗传角度而言 我们的孩子不能吃冷饮
也没法在游行时看得更远
to eat ice cream or ever
get a good view of a parade.
这些我还都能接受
But this?
但是这个?
This is a deal breaker.
这毁了我们的约定
Look on the bright side.
凡事总有两面
What's the bright side?
哪有好的一面?
Only nine more months to Comic-con.
离Comic-con动漫展只有九个月了
Oh, yeah.
噢 是啊
Captain, I'm getting an unusual reading.
队长 发现异常情况
Yeah, that's great.
那很好啊
- You guys want a corn dog?
- Yeah.
- 你们要来根玉米肠么?
- 好啊
That's a temporal anomaly.
时间异常
Corn dog's didn't come into existence
till the first half of the 20th century.
玉米肠是二十世纪中叶才出现的